welcome back Michael carer Barbara K
columnist with the National Post once a
week but writes Elsewhere on the
internet and blogging and so on and and
uh uh I I'm I'm not saying this just
because she's here she's only here
because I would say something like I
think she's one of the the the best most
courageous and original voices out there
now I have to say most voices are so Dar
and dumb I mean you look at a Roundup of
columns and and it's two opinions
expressed 30 people just repeating the
same old old uh mediocre nonsense let's
move on to the issue of um let's speak
about feminism here because surely um
your success your Triumph is a product
of of the feminist struggle you're a
free independent woman you can write
what you want but you seem quite hard on
on uh shall we say Hardline feminism I
am I consider feminism uh actually a a
very pernicious ideology and I do think
it is the ruling ideology of our time uh
and if you look at uh other struggles uh
gay rights all this it all becomes
subsumed under the general rubric of
feminism it's the best organized
Revolution I've ever seen it's a
bloodless Revolution um it's declared
enemies uh gave up without uh without a
fight um they declared themselves you
know prisoners of War without even
having to be rounded up and because it
is now entrenched uh in all educational
levels we are now because it's now 40
years on uh we're seeing the fruits of
that Revolution in um in the corridors
of power in all institutions where uh of
educational influence uh in the bar uh
where you know the majority of lawyers
are now women and many of them go into
uh teaching law because they are
strongly ideological uh we see the
influence all the way up to the Supreme
Court we see it in our social service
agencies we see it in our Charities uh
we see it there there there is no in
institution left in Canada uh that is
not heavily influenced by uh feminism
and politicians pay court to they know
that there there's uh a lot of uh bad
things will happen if you don't you know
if you're someone seeking power uh this
is one of the you know uh one of the
groups that you you really have to pay
attention to uh so uh because it is uh
an ideology and a revolutionary ideology
That Never Ends
um and because it is entrenched in the
educational system notably uh within
women's studies now called gender
studies most of the time but it's the
same old stuff in our universities uh it
permeates our society let's let's define
what it is because for many people uh it
would be uh equality equality of
opportunity same pay for the same effort
and work done um an awareness of
domestic violence uh rights within
marriage and these would would all be
self-evident truths now it's just a
popular assumption well I mean yes and
it is it started out that way uh in the
in the early years of the of the
movement it did begin as an equality
movement don't I please don't get the
impression that I think the
accomplishments of the feminist
Revolution are bad or wrong I mean
obviously but but to say that I could
speak my mind because of feminism simply
isn't true I I actually grew up in a pre
feminist Society I went to University in
a pre feminist environment I competed
against men at University I was never
treated as a second class citizen by my
male professors um so that's all
nonsense this whole thing that that
women uh before feminism came along uh
had no voice or had no power they had
different kinds of power but let's okay
let's let's grant that the feminist
Revolution is responsible for equal pay
and all that all these other wonderful
opportunities and of course equal
opportunity is something who could be
more in favor of it than you and me I
mean you you and I no you and me you and
I anyways um it went well beyond that
when you get to Second Stage feminism
you're now getting into a kind of
militancy uh where it's not about uh
equality for women it's about women's
interests and uh getting more it becomes
a zero sum game uh if men have any
advantages then they're taking it away
from women now this is just a wrong way
to look at Society uh so it sets up an
adversarial system where any rights men
have if women do not have at least equal
rights then they're being shafted uh and
we see now for instance in universities
where you have courses especially in
arts uh 70% women 80% some are up to 90%
women uh but everybody's extremely quiet
about it isn't this bad for men well
they don't care uh they really don't
care uh they as long as they're getting
what's good for women uh men can look
after themselves and they they they they
keep saying oh it's a man's world it's a
man's world you know this this just
isn't true anymore sociologically
speaking it's very much um uh A Woman's
World you mentioned domestic violence
this is something I write about a lot
because there's tremendous Injustice in
this area they're what 500 something
shelters uh for women not one for men um
men suffer from demestic violence almost
to the same degree that women do
Canadian stat stats Canada show
domestic violence is bilateral um it's
it's almost
50/50 yes women when it gets to the
violence stage which by the way is
extremely marginal uh if you look at the
whole domestic violence
picture and you look at the number of of
of extreme acts of violence it's so
nugatory that we we should set that
aside General violence hitting smacking
slapping knifing all this stuff is
almost 50/50 men don't talk about it men
won't go to theit hospital and say why
they're there with blood oozing out of
them you know they'll say they had an
accident um uh women are more violent to
Children than men are uh you don't hear
about any of this because it's one of
those closed subjects isn't it because
women spend more time with children
doesn't matter what it does show you is
that women are capable of violence H so
if they're capable of violence with
children why wouldn't they be capable of
violence with men they are they're
capable of violence with their
boyfriends um so
we it's one of those things you're not
allowed to talk about um there are men
who have nowhere to take their abused
children to protect them from their
mothers because there are no shelters
that will accept uh he can't go to the
Salvation Army with a kid uh women
shelters will accept women with their
children fleeing an abusive husband but
a father who wants to protect his small
children from an abusive mother there is
nowhere that he can go they he will be
accused of kidnapping and they'll now
that that is a very iniquitous situation
uh so there's a lot of Injustice Family
Court uh women have the advantage it's a
shocking advantage in custody issues uh
in family court and you know the there's
a bookshelf's been written on this
subject but it doesn't get into uh the
public forum it's not open for
discussion uh We've now got to the stage
where the best interests of the children
uh now coincide with the best interests
of of mothers that's that's really the
received wisdom on this uh fathers are a
forgotten group it's an orphan Topic in
the media I read about it as often as I
can but um you know if I write about it
too much then I begin to look like a
Ranter and an obsessive but it's
certainly one of the subjects very close
to my heart because I think that it's
just uh it's it's like a taboo subject
uh and things that that um uh men's pain
is is just not noticed and it's not
cared about uh and that's that's one of
those things that we've just sort of
accepted uh it's part of the air we
breathe uh it's it's what I call
misandry uh there there is a a kind of
dislike of men I should I shouldn't say
hatred but a a a sort of feeling men
don't matter men can be laughed at men
can be ridiculed men can be um uh spoken
of as a group as being um uh violent or
look the Montreal Massacre perfect
example the the white ribbon campaign
and the whole um the whole educational
system is full of the idea that men are
inherently violent uh that Mark lepine
is kind of somehow representative of a
strain in men that is almost Universal
that's a terrible thing to say about any
visible group uh I think think that I
think that it is a very divisive uh
philosophy just want to ask you two
things about the m one is that
um the Islamic context of of the
murderer is has been sponged from this
story the name that he originally had in
his father's name and so on the other
aspect is The Men Who allowed the women
to be separated and even allowed someone
to I'm I'm not I I would not be a hero
but if a if a group of us ran to stop
something I would certainly join in and
they allowed this person to to reload
they said yes to something which people
have said no to for many many years and
we've always condemned collaborators as
that also the latter a um a byproduct of
the feminist victory that men felt
emasculated and why was is the media so
terrified to mention that this man had
any Islamic Connection in his past well
the Islamic part they they are terrified
to mention it because uh that would put
them in a in in a a very bad double bind
because uh if you talk talk about him as
a generic male then you can say oh he's
violent he's this he's that and and and
all men share in his shame but if he if
the Islamic name is allowed in then
suddenly you're saying Muslims are
violent oo uh we can't have that so I
think that there was a deliberate
attempt to forget that he did come from
an extremely misogynist father who his
father beat his mother his father was
not religious was not a religious Muslim
and I am not saying Muslims are
inherently
what I'm saying is that uh from a media
point of view uh that just was not going
to fly because it interfered with the
more important feminist message that men
are bad and women are always victims the
second part the fact that the men
allowed it to happen I can't comment on
that because in the shock of um this
happening um it's very hard to say I
would have or they should have so I I
I'm a little leery about uh saying that
that is a factor the emasculation thing
you know I just don't want to say that I
there was a I'm not I'm not saying
they're identical but some years ago I
was a very young man at the time uh
there was a terrorist group in Northern
Ireland who who stopped a bus of workers
going to a job and they asked uh all the
uh one all all the Catholics to get out
and the Protestants said no no we're
together now it was a everyone was
killed in the end it was absolutely
horrible but it was a group of people
said no you're not going to do this
we're you're not going to separate we
are here together what a great thing and
that is not without precedent are other
people who said no you're not going to
do this and um I'm not I'm not blaming
any group for for bringing this
situation about but um it's uh it's an
interesting observation I think yes well
uh it's it's It's tricky to comment on
these things because um it was quite a I
mean it was a fairly unique situation
and and by the way uh unlike Ireland uh
violence in general in Quebec is uh it's
a very peaceful place Quebec so this was
kind of unprecedented on so many levels
uh that to blame people for not acting
in a
more as if they had thought it out or as
if they were already familiar with
situations like this think it's asking a
lot okay uh so I'll back off that I
won't I the one thing you've ever backed
off no no I'm you know when I when I
don't know when I don't know I'm I'm the
first one to admit it and uh oh it's
never stop me uh back a few moments on
the Michael gin show we'll see you soon
don't go away don't go away
welcome back Michael car show it's
halime and we sort of reintroduced the
panel at halim but it's a little bit
redundant here because it's only barbar
Kay only barbar Kay it is just the
single person barbar Kay columnist with
the national po um uh let's move subject
you met you mentioned victim groups The
Cult of victimhood that uh that women
have achieved over